얘들아, 안녕?
Oh, hey, you guys?
내 생일 저녁은 예약 못했어
I couldn't get a reservation
for the night of my birthday..
대신 목요일 저녁에 모이자
so we'll have to do dinner
Thursday night.
- 목요일? 할로윈데이잖아!
- 그래서?
- Thursday? But that's Halloween.
- So?
그냥 좀 으스스하다고
It's just spooky, that's all.
마이크도 오는거야?
So, is Mike coming to dinner?
애인과 맞는 첫번째 생일인데
하필 그날 야근이래
No. It's my first birthday
with a boyfriend, and he has to work.
화내고 싶지만 본색을 드러내기엔
아직 좀 이른것 같아
I'd get mad at him, but I think
it's too soon to show my true colors.
5명만 예약해, 우리중 하나는
엠마 봐야하니까
I would make the reservation for five.
One of us has to stay with Emma.
- 누가 가면 좋을까?
- 레이첼!
- Which one of us should go to dinner?
- Rachel!
우리 둘다 갈수있어
Actually, I was thinking
maybe both of us could go.
고맙다, 네 선물 특별히
더 신경 써서 준비할게
Thanks. I'll put a lot of extra thought
into your gift.
다 모일수 있으니 잘됐네
All right, so great, we can all go now.
재미있을 거야!
That is fun! Hey! You know what?
우리 모두 함께 모이는거
정말 오랜만이잖아
We all haven't been together,
the six of us, in such a long time.
무슨 소리야?
지금도 다같이 있잖아
What are you talking about?
We're together now.
모니카, 챈들러가 없잖아
Mon? Chandler's not here.
오, 이런!
Oh, dear God.
프렌즈 시즌 9
'피비의 생일'
'털사'
안녕하세요? 우리 팀
한자리에 모인거 처음이죠?
Hello. It's nice to see
our team together for the first time.
시작하기전에
질문 있으면 하세요
Now, before we get started,
are there any questions?
- 켄 맞죠?
- 맞습니다
- Yes. Ken, is it?
- That's right.
회의시간에 졸다가 얼떨결에
Is it true the reason you're in Tulsa is,
you fell asleep in a meeting..
털사에 오겠다고 했다던데
그게 사실인가요?
and took the job without realizing
what you were saying yes to?
소문을 다 믿지 말아요, 켄
Well, don't believe
everything you hear, Ken.
하지만 그건 사실입니다
But yeah, that's true.
그럼 지난 분기 실적부터
살펴볼까요?
All right, let's get started by taking
a look at last quarter's figures.
담배연기는 상사뒤통수에 대고
뿜는거 아닌가요?
Claudia, aren't you supposed
to blow smoke up the boss's ass?
죄송해요, 거슬리나요?
- I'm sorry. Does the smoke bother you?
- No. I smoked for years. Then I quit.
아뇨, 나도 담배 피웠어요
지금은 끊었지만
왜 끊었는지 모르겠어요
Right now, I can't remember why.
어쨌든 사무실에서는
금연 아닌가요?
You're not allowed to smoke
in this office, right?
오클라호마에서는
15인 이하일 경우 피워도 돼요
Yes, in Oklahoma it's legal to smoke
in offices with 15 people or less.
- 한대 필래요?
- 조이가 피자를 마다하겠어요?
- Would you like one?
- Would Joey like two pizzas?
제가 무슨 말을 하는지
모르겠군요
You don't know what I'm talking about.
아뇨, 난 담배끊었어요
All right, look. I don't smoke anymore.
하지만 피우고 싶은 사람은
얼마든지 펴요
But if the rest of you want to light up,
go ahead, it's fine.
다들 피는군요
So, you all smoke, then?
담배 안피는게
민망할 지경이네
You know, it's almost rude
that I'm not smoking.
- 괜찮아요, 피우기 싫으면..
- 켄, 제발!
- That's not true. If you don't want..
- Ken, please!
난 담배 피면 안돼요
집사람한테 죽거든요
No, I can't. I can't smoke.
If I smoke, my wife would kill me.
부인은 뉴욕에 있지 않나요?
I'm sorry, but isn't your wife
back in New York?
난 켄이 늘 마음에 들었어요
I've always liked you, Ken.
사탕 안주면 장난 칠거야!
Trick or treat.
와, 사탕보다 더 근사한걸?
- Hey.
- And "treat" it is.
옷 갈아입길 잘했네
Wow. So glad I changed.
낡아서 가슴이 다 삐져나오는
옷 입으려고 했거든
I almost wore my threadbare robe
that can't contain my breasts.
내 취향 아냐
요즘 배란기인데
This is not what I'm wearing.
I'm ovulating..
챈들러가 곧 올거거든
저녁식사 전에 시도하려고
and Chandler's gonna be home. So,
I thought we would try before dinner.
다같이 가려고 했는데
Oh, I thought we'd all
go over together.
식당에서 만나지뭐
All right, I'll just meet you there
at dinner.
네가 원하다면, 남아서
지켜봐 줄수도 있고
Unless, I mean, if it helps,
I could stay and watch.
- 싫어!
- 사실은, 나도 싫었어
- No!
- Well, I didn't want to anyway.
그냥, 도움이 될까봐서
물어본거야
You know, just thought
I'd be polite and offer.
그러다 내 생일파티에
늦는건 아니지?
Wait, does this mean you'll be late?
우리 일주일 넘게 못봤어
We haven't seen each other
in over a week.
우리가 제일 먼저 도착할걸?
We'll probably be the first ones there.
그럼 식당에서 봐
잘해봐!
Okay. See you there. Happy humping.
- 챈들러!
- 안녕
Hey. Well, hey!
어머!
누가 담배 피웠나?
Wow, somebody smoked out here?
어쩜, 공공장소에선
금연이란걸 모르나봐!
My God, don't people know you're
not allowed to smoke in public spaces?
오클라호마에선 15인 이하일때
공공장소에서 담배 피워도 돼
Actually, in Oklahoma smoking's legal
in offices with fewer than 15 people.
너 담배 피웠구나
Oh, you smoked.
아니, 담배에 대한 잡다한
지식을 알게 된것 뿐이야
No. I just happen to know a lot of trivia
about smoking in different states.
하와이에서는 담배를
레이-라나-루쿠스라고 한대
For example, in Hawaii,
cigarettes are called lei-lana-lukus.
- 너 담배 냄새 나!
- 모니카가 알아차릴까?
- Oh, Chandler, you stink of cigarettes!
- Do you think Monica will smell it?
그걸 말이라고 해?
걔 사냥개 코잖아!
Are you kidding? That woman
has the nose of a bloodhound.
가슴은 여신의 가슴이지
And the breasts of a Greek goddess.
피비?
Phoebe?
나 갈게
I'm gonna go.
담배 냄새 뭐로 가리지?
Okay. Something to cover the smell.
오븐 세제!
Oven cleaner.
향이 없다고?!
Unscented.
어서와!
Welcome home.
보고 싶었어
I've missed you.
- 침실로 들어오지 그래?
- 아니, 됐어
- You want to join me in the bedroom?
- No, thanks, I'm good.
알았어
오늘 주제는 튕기기야?
Okay. So you want to play it
that way, do you?
나 방금 비행기에서 내려서
Well, you know what, actually,
I just got off a plane..
너무 지저분해
샤워부터 할게
so I'm feeling gross.
I should take a shower.
- 샤워할 필요없어
- 알았어, 실은 말야..
- Come here, you don't need a shower.
- All right, the truth is..
난 기류 때문에
비행기안에서 실수를 했어
I soiled myself
during some turbulence.
이게 무슨 냄새지?
담배 냄새잖아!
What do I smell? I smell smoke.
담배 폈어?
Did you smoke?
그래! 딱 한대 폈어
Yes. But I just had one.
두대
Two.
딱 두대 폈어
알았어! 다섯대야!
Two tiny cigarettes. Okay, five.
한갑!
두갑.. 한보루!
A pack. Two pack.. A carton.
이틀동안 담배 세보루 폈다!
Three big fat cartons in two days!
하지만 끝이야
다시는 담배 안필거야!
But it's over. I've made a decision,
I'm not gonna smoke anymore.
그건 자기 선물이야
Well, those are for you.
알았어요
그럼 이따봐요
All right. Well, we'll just see you
when you get here. Bye.
엄마야
길이 엄청 막힌대
Oh, that was my mom.
She's stuck in terrible traffic.
이건 엠마 두고 가지 말라는
세번째 계시야
That is now the third sign
that I should not leave Emma.
- 다른 두가지는 뭔데?
- 첫번째, 가고 싶지 않다
- What are the other two?
- Well, the first one is, I don't want to.
두번째, 안갈거다
And second one, I'm not going.
아기 두고 외출하는거
처음이라 긴장되겠지
I know this is the first time
we're leaving the baby.
얼마나 힘든지 알아
I know how hard it is for you. But..
하지만 별일 없을거야
엄마가 와서 봐주실 거잖아
But everything's gonna be fine.
I mean, my mom is gonna be with her.
- 울 엄마 아기 아주 잘보셔
- 정말?
- She's great with kids.
- She is?
그럼
Yeah.
근데 모니카는 왜저래?
What about Monica?
모니카 얘기만 들어서 그래!
그 뚱보가 얼마나 고약했다고!
You only hear Monica's side of that.
Okay, that little fatso was a terror!
- 도저히 못가겠어
- 할수있어, 그래야만 하구
- I just don't think I can do it.
- Know what? You can and you should.
너한테도 좋은 일이야
Really, it will be good for you.
그러지 말고
In fact, you know what?
먼저가
난 엄마 오시면 갈게
Go ahead to the restaurant,
and I will wait for my mom..
식당에서 만나자
안돼, 가야해, 어서 나가!
and then I'll meet you there.
No, no, really, you should go. Go out.
세상은 전부 네거야!
넌 자유인이라구!
Really, the world is your oyster.
Kick up your heels. Paint the town red!
자유를 맘껏 즐겨!
- 웬만하면 새로운 표현좀 익혀라
- 농담아냐, 어서가, 어서!
- You need to learn some new slang.
- I'm serious. Come on, you should go.
자, 어서가!
Here. No, just go.
- 그치만..
- 안돼!
- Well..
- No, no! You know what?
다신 못들어가!
애는 괜찮으니까 가라구!
You're not getting back in there!
The baby's fine. Now, scram!
눈썹 날리게 뛰어!
Yeah, hit the bricks!
어서 가시죠, 사모님!
Tell your story walking!
나 열쇠 두고 나왔어
I was just going to say
that I left my keys.
아이구, 이런! 우째 이런일이!
Holy moley, are we in a pickle now!
다들 어떻게 된거야?
40분이나 지났잖아!
Where is everyone?
They're 40 minutes late.
- 그러게 말야
- 배고파
- I know.
- I'm starving.
오늘 저녁 기대하고
하루종일 굶었단 말야
I knew we were coming here tonight.
I ate nothing all day.
난 어떻고?
점심 한끼밖에 안먹었어
What about me?
I only had one lunch today.
다른 분들도 곧
오실건가요?
So, are we expecting
the rest of our party shortly?
네, 금방 올거예요
Yes, they are expected presently.
Yeah.
머지않아 도착할 겁니다
Their arrival is in the offing.
좌석 두개짜리 테이블로 옮기시면
Right. We have a table for two available.
- 더 편하실 텐데..
- 금방 온다니까요!
- Perhaps you'd..
- No, they're coming.
여기서 기다릴 거예요!
We're waiting right here.
조이!
Joseph!
걱정 말아요
곧 올거니까
One needn't worry.
They shan't be long.
여럿이 함께 오신 팀이
대기중이라서요
It's just that we do have
some large parties waiting.
싫다는데 참 질기시네요
Oh, one really does have a stick
up one's ass, doesn't one?
왜 담배를 다시 피우는 거야?
건강에 얼마나 해로운데
Why would you start smoking again?
It's so bad for you.
이틀밖에 안됐어
그걸로 죽지는..
It's only been two days.
That's not enough time to..
이건 담배랑 상관없어
That's totally unrelated.
어떻게 요즘 같은 시대에
담배를 펴? 광고도 안봤어?
How can you smoke in this day and age?
Have you not seen that ad?
꼬마애가 할아버지 되는거?
소름도 안끼쳐?
Where the little kid walks
through Grandpa? It's chilling!
잠깐 정신 나갔었어
회의시간에 다들 피우더라고
I messed up. It was a meeting.
Everybody was smoking.
그래서?
그만한 자제력도 없어?
So what? Don't you have any willpower?
자제력?
옛날 비디오 보니까
Willpower? I've watched home movies
of you eating Ding Dongs..
자긴 포장지도 안벗기고
초콜릿 먹더라!
without taking the tinfoil off!
그거 섹시하댔잖아!
You said that was sexy!
그만 싸우자
다신 안피울게
Okay, look, can we just drop this?
I'm not gonna smoke again.
좋아
다신 용납 안할거니까
That's right, because I forbid you
to smoke again.
- 용납 안해?
- 그래
You forbid me?
사랑스런 마누라 보러
먼길을 날아왔더니
I've flown a long way
to see my loving wife.
혹시 우리 마누라 못봤어?
Is she here, by the way?
농담하지마!
나 지금 굉장히 화났어!
Chandler, don't joke with me. Okay?
I'm very, very upset right now.
더이상 화날수
없을만큼 많이?
- Is this the most upset you could be?
- I think so.
그래
그렇다면 난..
Well, then I might as well..
한대 펴야지
do this.
이 다음엔 뭘 어떡해야
할지 모르겠다
Not really sure what to do now.
뭘 해야할지 말해주지
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
피비의 생일 만찬에는
어차피 늦었어
We're already late
for Phoebe's birthday dinner.
그러니까 그 담배 당장 끄고
So you're going to put out
that cigarette..
싸움도 중지하고 침대로 가는거야
we're gonna put this fight on hold,
and go have sex.
좋아! 뭐라구?
Fine. What?
담배를 귀에다 꽂았어
왜 못알아들어?
What, do you have
cigarettes in your ears?
침대! 배란기 마지막 날이야!
Sex! This is the last day I'm ovulating.
If we don't do it..
지금 안하면 한달 기다려야해!
we're gonna have to wait
until next month!
진심이야?
You're serious?
물론이야!
- Oh, yeah!
- All right, fine, I'll do it, but no talking!
좋아! 하지뭐!
대신 말 안하기야!
- 껴안지도 마!
- 목에 뽀뽀도 안할거야!
- And no cuddling.
- And no kissing your neck.
좋아! 안그래도
그거 너무 싫었어!
Oh, good! I hate it when you do that!
목에 마구 뽀뽀해주마!
And lots of kissing your neck!
관리인을 못찾겠어
Okay, well, the super's not home.
엄마 곧 오실거잖아
엄마한테 열쇠 있어
But my mother's gonna be here,
and she has the key.
그때까지 못기다려!
어떻게 좀 해봐! 부숴 버려!
I can't wait that long. You have to do
something. Knock that door down!
그럼 나 병원가야해
I would, but I bruise like a peach.
괜찮을 테니까 걱정마
엠마는 자고 있어
Besides, you know, everything's
gonna be fine. The baby's sleeping.
요람에서 뛰어나오면 어떡해?
- What if she jumps out of the bassinet?
- Can't hold her head up, but jumped.
고개도 못 가누는 애가
잘도 뛰어나오겠다
어떡해!
수돗물 틀어놓고 왔어!
Oh, my God!
I left the water running!
수돗물 안틀어놨어
제발 침착해
You did not leave the water running.
Please, pull yourself together, okay?
- 가스 불 켜놓지 않았나?
- 96년 이후로 요리한적 없잖아!
- Well, did I leave the stove on?
- You haven't cooked since 1996.
창문 열어놓지 않았어?
만약 창문으로 새가 들어와서..
Is the window open? If the window's
open a bird could fly in and..
맙소사, 자기말이
맞는것 같아
My God, you know what?
I think you're right.
- 들어봐
- 왜? 뭔데?
- Listen.
- What? What?
비둘기소리야! 아냐
독수리가 날아 들어왔어!
A pigeon. No. No, wait, no.
An eagle flew in!
가스렌지 위에 앉았다가
불이 붙었네!
Landed on the stove and caught fire!
엠마가 그걸보고 뛰어올라
새를 구하러 갔어!
The baby, seeing this, jumps across
the apartment to the mighty bird's aid.
독수리는
자길 잡으려는줄 알고
The eagle, however, misconstrues this
as an act of aggression..
애를 발톱으로 낚아챘어!
and grabs the baby in its talon.
그동안 수돗물이 계속
흘러서 집안에 가득 찼는걸!
Meanwhile, the faucet
fills the apartment with water.
엠마랑 불타는 독수리가
Baby and bird, still ablaze,
are locked in a death grip..
소용돌이에 휘말린채 갇혀있어!
swirling around the whirlpool
that fills the apartment!
그게 사실이라면
후회하게 될거야
Boy, are you gonna be sorry
if that's true.
- 실례합니다
- 네
- Hello.
- Hi.
한시간이 넘었습니다
It's been an hour.
지배인이 작은 테이블로
옮기시는게 어떠시냐는데요?
The maitre d' asked if you'd reconsider
switching to a smaller table.
지금 그냥 주문하자
Maybe we should just eat now.
다른분들 오실 때까지는 주문하실
수 없습니다, 저희 식당 규칙이죠
You can't order until the entire
party's arrived. Restaurant policy.
이건 어때요?
테이블이 하나 비었어요
Well, how about this?
Another table leaves, right..
그런데 손님들이
음식을 남겼죠
but there's still some food left
on their plates.
그걸 먹는것에 대해
여기 규칙은 어떻죠?
Okay, what's the restaurant's policy
about people eating that?
- 눈살을 찌푸리겠죠
- 하지만 그런일도 있죠?
- It's frowned upon.
- But it happens.
- 나 화장실 다녀올게
- 안돼!
- All right, I got to go to the bathroom.
- You can't go.
나 혼자선
이 테이블 못지켜
No, no, no.
I can't hold this table on my own.
옮기라고 하면
난 버틸 자신 없어!
If they ask me to move, I'll cave.
화장실 못가게 하면
난 여기서 싸야해
Well, if you ask me to stay, I'll pee.
실례합니다
Good evening, miss.
손님?
Miss?
손님!
Miss? Miss?
알았어요, 옮길게요!
힘까지 쓸건 없잖아요!
Okay, fine, I'll move. All right.
You don't have to manhandle me.
어디죠?
- Where?
- Okay.
고마워요, 와!
Thank you. Wow.
이제 그만좀 노려보실래요?
Will you stop staring at us now?
그거야, 손님 친구분께서 올리브유를
병째 마시지 않는다면요
That depends. Will your friend stop
drinking olive oil directly from the bottle?
할수 없군요
Probably not.
너희들 드디어 왔구나!
Finally. You guys made it.
피비, 이 사람들.. 으악!
Phoebe, who the hell..?
뭘그리 꾸물거려?
빨리 해치우자구!
What is taking you so long,
Come on, let's get it over with!
잠깐만 기다려봐
In a minute, sweet cakes.
넥타이 붙잡고 아예 밤을 새라!
애가 잘도 생기겠다!
Spend more time with the tie!
That will make a baby.
도저히 못하겠어
이렇게 싸우면서 어떻게 해!
Look, I can't do this. I can't make love
to you while we're fighting this way.
그러셔?
예민하기도 하셔라!
Oh, sure. Now you're Mr. Sensitivity.
우리 삼촌 장례식 직후에
몸달아 했던건 누구지?
But when you wanted to have sex
after my uncle's funeral..
그건 삶에 대한 찬미였어!
That was a celebration of life!
난 이런 식으론 못해
All right, I'm not gonna do this.
우리 아기를 정말
이런식으로 가지고 싶어?
Is this the way you want our baby
to be conceived?
아니, 자기 말이 맞아
No, you're right.
이건 옳지않아
We shouldn't do it like this.
어쨌든 나도 미안해
For what it's worth, I'm sorry.
그렇게 몰아세울 것까진
없었는데
I shouldn't have come down on you
so hard about the smoking.
담배 몇개피 폈기로
세상이 끝나는 것도 아닌데 말야
So you had a few cigarettes.
It's not the end of the world.
- 정말?
- 그래
- Really?
- Yeah.
자긴 정말 대단해
You are incredible.
다시는 안필게
And listen,
I'm not gonna smoke again.
또 그러면 그땐 진짜
안들키게 잘 감출게
And if I do, I promise
I will hide it so much better from you.
- 할래?
- 그래, 삶을 찬미하자고!
- Want to?
- Let's celebrate life!
좋아!
Okay!
오!
Oh, God.
무사했구나!
Oh, thank God you're okay.
혼자 둬서 미안해
엄마가 다신 너 혼자 안둘게
I'm sorry we left.
Mommy will never leave you again.
다시는 절대로!
Never, ever, ever again.
그럼 이만 갈까?
Great. So let's get going.
나 진심으로 한말이야
I mean it. After what just happened,
I'm never leaving her again.
이런 일까지 있었는데
다신 엠마 곁을 안떠날거야
이해한다
애 떼어두기 힘들지
I understand. Separation is hard.
한번은 로스 혼자 두고
미용실에 가려고 했더니
One time I was about to leave Ross
to go to the beauty parlor.
얘가 겁을 먹고는 옷을
다 벗어버리는 거야
And he got so upset
he took off all his clothes..
그리고 고추를
다리 사이에 감추고는
tucked his willy between his legs..
소릴 질렀지! "엄마, 저 여자예요!
저도 데려가요!"
and cried out, "Mommy, I'm a girl.
Take me with you."
시간이 흘러 이젠 엄마랑
떨어지는게 훨씬 쉬워졌어요
Somehow, over time,
it got easier to be apart from you.
남편 잘뒀지
You are welcome.
- 자기랑 말하기 싫어
- 뭐?
- You know what? Let's not talk.
- What?
- 나 아직도 화 안풀렸어!
- 용서 한댔잖아!
- I am still so mad at you for smoking!
- But you said you forgave me.
- 담배 몇개피 별거 아니라며!
- 별거 아닌거 좋아하네!
It was just a couple of cigarettes,
no big deal.
배란기라 거짓말 한거야!
싸우면서는 하기 싫다길래!
I was ovulating and you said you
wouldn't have sex if we were fighting.
날 침대로 끌어들이려고
거짓말 한거야?
- You tricked me to get me into bed?
- That's right. I got mine.
그래! 그게 내 식이야!
완전히 이용당했군
I feel so used.
애들 안올건가봐
그냥 주문할래?
Well, I guess they're not coming.
You want to just order?
고마워!
Thank you.
웨이터!
빨리 말할 거니까 잘들어요
Waiter? All right, this is gonna
go fast, so try to keep up.
얇게 저민 송로버섯 리조토랑
Risotto with shaved truffles
and the rib steak..
살구버섯 곁들인 립 스테이크
with the golden chanterelles
and the Bordelaise sauce..
그중에 '달팽이' 들어가는거
있음 빼구요
unless any of that stuff I just said
means "snails."
그런건 없습니다
It does not.
토마토 타르트
이중에 어떤 파스타가 맛있죠?
Tomato tart, and which of the pastas
would you recommend?
- 둘다 훌륭하죠
- 그럼 둘다 주세요
- Oh, well they're both exquisite..
- Both it is. Thank you.
드디어 먹을 시간이다
음식 챙겨와, 웨이터 양반
Now, let's go, baby.
It's food time. Bring it, bitch.
- 죄송해요
- 괜찮습니다
- Sorry about that.
- It's quite all right.
특별 주문해도 될까요?
Oh, can I make a special request?
뭐든 되는대로
빨리 갖다줄래요?
Can you bring everything
as it's ready?
- 전채, 후식, 가리지 말고..
- 우리 왔어!
- Appetizers, entrees, we don't care.
- Hey!
- 메뉴 정하실 때까지 기다리죠
- 제가 무슨 실수라도 했나요?
- I'll wait to put your order in.
- What did I ever do to you?
전혀요, 손님 양반
Nothing, bitch.
한시간이나 늦었잖아
You guys are over an hour late.
- 어떻게 된거야?
- 정말 미안해
- What happened to you two?
- So sorry.
열쇠를 두고 나왔지 뭐야
- We got locked out of the apartment.
- That's a great story. Can I eat it?
대단한 얘기구나!
그거 먹을수 있니?
그랬더니 레이첼이 애 혼자두고
갈수 없다잖아
And then Rachel wasn't sure
she could leave the baby.
쉽지 않았지만 네 생일이라
용기를 냈지
It wasn't easy, but it's your birthday
and I did what I had to do.
저기 엠마랑 같이 있는분
로스 어머님 아냐?
And that's Judy over there at the bar
with Emma?
어쩔수 없었어
이렇게 해야 엠마 걱정 안하고
This is for the best. I'm not distracted,
worrying about Emma..
너희랑 좋은 시간 보내지
how she's doing at home, and I'm
gonna be completely here with you.
- 어머, 엠마가 침흘리네!
- 뭐?
- Oh, she spit up. She spit up.
- What?
침 흘린다구! 어머님
엠마가 침을.. 빨리요!
Judy? She spit..
Judy, look alive, Judy!
- 고마워요
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
다 맛있을것 같은데?
Oh, everything looks delicious.
뭘 먹지?
뭘 먹으면 좋을까?
What should I have?
여자는 절대
때리지 말자!
Never hit a woman.
그러게!
다 맛있겠다!
I know what you mean,
this menu's incredible.
로스, 넌 죽었어!
가만 두나 봐라!
Ross bruises like a peach.
He bruises like a peach.
무화과 샐러드와
오리요리로 주세요
Okay, I'll have the fig salad
and the duck.
난 수프하고 연어
I'll have the soup and the salmon.
알죠?
뭐든 나오는 대로
Remember, whatever comes up first,
okay?
- 빨리..
- 해피 버스데이!
- Hurry..
- Happy birthday!
망할것들!
Son of a bitch!
- 어떻게 된거야!
- 둘이 좀 싸웠어
- Where have you been?
- Well, we had a little fight.
사람 침대로 끌어들이자고
거짓말을 해?
I would never lie
to get someone into bed.
자긴 여자들한테 전생에
케네디였다고 했잖아!
You used to tell girls
you were a Kennedy.
고마워요
Thanks.
고마워요, 와
Thanks. Wow.
좀 좁다
큰 테이블 예약하지 그랬어?
A little tight, isn't it?
Why didn't you get a bigger table?
큰 테이블 예약했는데
쫓겨난 거구나
You had a big table
but they made you move.
입 다물어야지
Shut up, Monica.
챈들러는 '연기'에 그을린
오리가 좋겠지?
Oh, well, I suppose that Chandler
will have the smoked duck.
자긴 '남편 속여서
이용해먹는 마누라 찜' 먹을래?
And I suppose that Monica
will have the manipulative shrew.
그런게 있었어?
How did I miss that?
- 다시 오겠습니다
- 어디가는 거예요!
- I'll give you another minute.
- What, where you going?
'마누라찜' 달라잖아!
He said she wanted the shrew!
레이첼, 엠마는 괜찮아
Rach, come on, Emma's fine.
자기 너무 심한거 알아?
적당히 해
You're turning into an obsessive
mother, okay? You need to stop.
너희들 로스 어머님이
미용실 가실때 얘기 들었니?
You ever hear the story about when
Ross' mom went to the beauty salon?
- '고추'이야기 말야?
- 하! 벌써들 알고 있지롱!
- You mean the willy story?
- They already know it.
너희들 기다리느라 지쳤어
We've been waiting for you
for a long time.
- 주문하자
- 됐어
- You should order.
- That's okay.
- 내가 얘들것도 주문했어
- 네가 왜?
- I told the waiter what they want.
- Why would you do that?
챈들러, 네 마누라좀
어떻게 해라!
Chandler, control your woman.
좋아
다들 주문했으니까
Okay, well..
Everybody has ordered.
I would like to start the celebration
and make a toast to Phoebe.
피비의 생일을 축하하는
건배 하자
피비를 위하여!
- 양말 떨어졌네
- 뭐?
- She dropped her sock.
- What?
엠마 양말이 떨어졌어
No. No, Emma dropped her sock.
- 그걸 어떻게 알아?
- 저기 있거든
- How do you know that?
- She's over there.
- 엄마랑 같이
- 엄마가 오셨어?
- Mom's with her.
- Mom's here?
점심 같이 하쟀더니
바쁘다고 하셔놓고!
I wanted to have lunch with her today.
She told me she was out of town.
아직도 엠마 양말 떨어진거
모르고 계셔
She still has not noticed
that the baby's sock is on the ground.
참 멋진 건배다
It's a good toast.
어머님 좀 불러봐
Look, will you please get her attention?
엄마?
Mommy?
어머님
Mother.
오, 젠장! 로스 어머님!
양말 주으세요!
Oh, for God's sake, Judy,
pick up the sock!
양말 주으세요!
양말! 양말이요!
Pick up the sock! Pick up the sock!
미안! 내가 좀 무례했니?
I'm sorry, was that rude?
내 성질좀 폭발한게
Did my little outburst..
이 끔찍한 분위기를 망친거야?
blunt the hideousness
that is this evening?
모두들 나름대로
사정이 있다는거 알아
Look, I know you have a lot going on..
난 단지 생일에 친구들과
오붓한 저녁을 먹고 싶었던 건데
but all I wanted to do was have
dinner with my friends on my birthday.
모두들 늦게 오면서
어쩜 전화 한통도 안하니!
And you are all so late, and you
didn't even have the courtesy to call.
이젠 너무 늦었어!
Well, it's too late now.
우리가 건거 아냐
Phoebe, I don't think that's us.
어, 그럼..
내말 다 안끝났어!
Oh, well, this is.. This is not over!
Hello?
여보세요?
너무 미안하다, 우리가 마음을
굳게 먹고 일찍 나와야 했어
I feel terrible. We should've been strong
and left Emma at home.
우리?
"We"?
얘들이 모르는 고추 얘기 할까?
There are some adult willy stories
they don't know.
We should've been stronger.
우리가 마음을 굳게 먹어야 했어
- 너희들은 왜 싸운거야?
- 나 요즘 배란기야
- What is going on with you two?
- Well, you see, I'm ovulating.
말은 그렇게 하지
Oh, yeah, that's what she says.
하지만 누가 알겠어? 날 침대로
끌어들이기 위한 거짓말일지!
Maybe you're not ovulating. Maybe
it's a clever ruse to get me into bed.
그래, 이 굴뚝아! 거짓말이다
도무지 성에 안차서 말야
Yeah, Smokey, that's what it was.
I just can't get enough.
이게 말이 되니?
얘 거짓말했어!
You're not gonna believe this.
날 속여서 침대로
끌어들였다구
She tricked me
into having sex with her.
그래서?
너희들 애 가질 거라며
So? You got to have sex, right?
나 왜 이러지?
왜 계집애처럼 구는걸까?
What's the matter with me?
Why am I such a girl?
- 마이크 전화야
- 피비, 정말 미안해
- Okay. That was Mike.
- Oh, Phoebe, honey, we are so sorry.
네말이 맞아
우리 집중할게
You are totally right.
We are here 100 percent..
사랑해
네 생일 맘껏 축하해 줄게
and we love you, and we are ready
to start your birthday celebration.
오, 너무 고맙다!
You guys, that means the world to me.
나 가봐야겠어
Okay, I'm gonna take off.
뭐?
What?
나도 너희들 사랑하는데
마이크 일이 일찍 끝났대
I love you guys too, but,
Mike got off work early.
잠깐!
Wait.
난 남자친구 때문에 친구들
I'm not the.. I'm not the kind of girl
that just ditches her friends..
팽개치는 그런 애가 아냐
to be with her boyfriend.
아냐, 난 그런 애야
You know what? I am.
잘있어!
어머님, 저 갈게요!
Bye, guys. Judy! Bye.
피비도 갔는데
엠마 데리고 집에 갈래?
If Phoebe's gone,
can we take Emma home?
그러는게 좋겠어
엄마가 포도주 한병 더 시켰어
That's a good idea. Our babysitter
just pounded another chardonnay.
- 우리 갈게
- 잘가
- Bye, you guys.
- Bye.
잘가라
우리 뿐이네
See you. Well, I guess it's just us.
나 아직 배란중인데
한번 더 시도해볼래?
So, I'm probably still ovulating.
Do you want to give it another try?
그래
All right.
케네디하고 한번도 안해봤지?
So, you've never had sex
with a Kennedy, have you?
사실은, 리차드의 외가쪽이
케네디가야
Actually, Richard was a Kennedy
on his mother's side.
그 남자랑 도대체
왜 헤어진거야?
Why did you break up with that guy?
- 지금 하러 간다구?
- 시간이 많지 않아
- You're gonna go do it?
- We don't have much time.
일단 난자가 나팔관으로
내려오면..
Once the egg descends
into the fallopian tube..
그만! 얼른 가봐!
Oh, wait, oh, get out of here!
다른분들 다시
돌아오시는 거겠죠?
I sincerely hope the rest of your party
is returning.
아뇨, 저뿐이에요
저 혼자죠
No, just me. All alone.
와, 혼자서 6인분이라..
Dinner for six for one.
여러분은 오늘 보기 드문걸
보게 될겁니다
Well, you boys are about
to see something really special.
- 어떠셨습니까?
- 아주 맛있었어요
- How was everything?
- Excellent.
특히 '마누라찜'이 끝내주더군요
The shrew, in particular, was exquisite.
아직 끝난게 아닙니다
I hope you've got some room left.
생일 축하합니다
사랑하는..
조이에요, 조이!
Joey. Joey.
사랑하는 조이
생일 축하합니다!
최고의 생일이에요!
This is the best birthday ever!